<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanzil Zubair Bin Zaman</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tanzil Zubair Bin Zaman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Chroma, my 2nd app!!</title>
      <link>/projects/chroma-mind-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/chroma-mind-spaces/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chroma&#39;s website!</title>
      <link>/projects/chroma-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/chroma-website/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morbus, my 1st prize winning game!</title>
      <link>/projects/morbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/morbus/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Valedictorian - My Thoughts</title>
      <link>/blog/being-valedictorian-my-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 07:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/being-valedictorian-my-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>On the 15th of June, this year, as Valedictorian, I gave a speech on the graduation ceremony of my batch, addressing my friends, my teachers, our supervisors, and everyone else present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecting a Flutter app…and it’s importance</title>
      <link>/blog/architecting-a-flutter-app-and-why-it-s-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/architecting-a-flutter-app-and-why-it-s-important/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This article is written to discuss and provide a beginner friendly perspective on architecture, why it’s important, and how to implement it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter Apps :3</title>
      <link>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 07:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This is Part 3 and the final part of a series of articles that explore and seek to provide newcomers with a high-level overview of what all the parts of a Flutter app consist of and do, so that they can hit the ground running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter Apps :2</title>
      <link>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 07:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This is Part 2 of a series of articles that explore and seek to provide newcomers with a high-level overview of what all the parts of an app consist of and do, so that they can hit the ground running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An OpenWeather API Interface, my second package!</title>
      <link>/projects/an-openweather-api-interface-my-second-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/an-openweather-api-interface-my-second-package/</guid>
      <description>Re-Inventing The Wheel There’s a saying well known by most programmers “Don’t reinvent the wheel’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter Apps :1</title>
      <link>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/what-goes-into-a-flutter-app-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This article is meant to be a starting point for people new to coding and trying their hand at Dart and Flutter, much as I was and did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caelum: Beautiful Weather</title>
      <link>/projects/caelum-beautiful-weather/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/caelum-beautiful-weather/</guid>
      <description>Familiar Faces The heading here might not make sense, but stick with me here, and I promise it will by the end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caelum&#39;s website!</title>
      <link>/projects/caelum-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/caelum-website/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, but even better (The Third)</title>
      <link>/blog/this-website-but-even-better-the-third/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/this-website-but-even-better-the-third/</guid>
      <description>Under The Hood Where to even start. This update, apart from being massive in both development time and lines of code edited (or even added) was also quite underwhelming in that a significant portion of the improvements have no visual footprint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Ghost In The Shell</title>
      <link>/blog/an-ode-to-titanfall-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 16:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/an-ode-to-titanfall-2/</guid>
      <description>Humans are&amp;hellip;.. impressionable beings by nature, a trait caused by the immense adaptability we are gifted with, the very thing that took us from hunter gatherers to the dominant lifeforms on this planet, from rubbing rocks together to make fire to terraforming the planet to our needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make X: Part 2</title>
      <link>/blog/how-do-i-make-x-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 11:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-do-i-make-x-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Codename VT-7274 So, before we begin, let me lay out my idea for the project that we&amp;rsquo;ll be using as an example for how to flesh out ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, but better</title>
      <link>/blog/this-website-but-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/this-website-but-better/</guid>
      <description>The Sparkly One Update 2.0 of my site brings about a huge number of visual upgrades to the site, overhauls the site traversal menu (turning it into menus) and sets the groundwork for both Update 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I make X ?</title>
      <link>/blog/how-do-i-make-x-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 07:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-do-i-make-x-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Preambles Ideas are a fickle, elusive thing. They come to us in droves, or sometimes not at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first Flutter package!!</title>
      <link>/projects/mobx-architecture-my-first-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/mobx-architecture-my-first-package/</guid>
      <description>The Inspiration The internet is a big place, and getting bigger everyday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Website, V:1.0.0!</title>
      <link>/projects/this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/this-website/</guid>
      <description>This Website! Yes, this website!. Built using HTML, Javascript and CSS (along with libraries to ease the pain of boilerplate code) , with Hugo as the CMS and Forestry mixed in for a little GUI convenience, this is my little space on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Minecraft Mod!</title>
      <link>/projects/minecraft-nuclear-weapons-add-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/minecraft-nuclear-weapons-add-on/</guid>
      <description>The Beginning Ahh, my first coding project. Minecraft is something that I’ve loved all my life, the joy, the freedom, the boundless possibilities spreading out before you every time you open a world….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Heus! Hello! My name is Tanzil. I am an amateur coder, with a habit of jumping into things way over my head, and hacking away at them till I can finally thank god wrangle them enough to make what I had originally set out to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-2/</guid>
      <description>My Hobbies Besides this, writing is also one of my hobbies, ironically having grown more when I no longer had English as a subject in school anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Initium In the Beginning I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by technology since as long as I can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Aut cum scuto aut in scuto One way or the other It was a forbidden place of untold magic to me, the world behind the proverbial curtains, if only sealed off by near impenetrable walls of undecipherable code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Per aspera ad astra Through hardships, to the stars Each time I ventured into these glitches, the few I could manage to find at all that is, I felt like Miles Morales, donning my mask and diving into cyberspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Destitutus ventis, remos adhibe Whatever it takes It was hard, mainly because the developers of that time didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of being able to update their games after it hit shelves, so basically all but the most obscure of bugs were caught when testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Et Ipsa Scientia Potestas Est And knowledge itself, is power I also vividly remember, looking around at all of the electronics surrounding me, things we more often than not take for granted, from the television in the living room to the oven in the kitchen, and the endless sense of bewilderment and wonder that would consume my mind when trying to understand or predict how they worked (and later on when I would take them apart to see for myself).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Sine Qua Non The indispensable reason why And so, driven by a feverish requirement, my hands soon became nimble enough to take apart and reliably be able to put back together quite a lot of things, from remote controlled cars and helicopters to flashlights and blenders and even part of an oven once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-9/</guid>
      <description>Per inānem in scrūtātione īnfīnī Through the void in search of the infinite It has been years, since I wrote that first line of JSON for my Minecraft mod, and years more since I&amp;rsquo;ve loaded up a game on my Gameboy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
