<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on Tanzil Zubair Bin Zaman</title>
    <link>/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on Tanzil Zubair Bin Zaman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-1/</guid>
      <description>Heus! Hello! My name is Tanzil. I am an amateur coder, with a habit of jumping into things way over my head, and hacking away at them till I can finally thank god wrangle them enough to make what I had originally set out to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-2/</guid>
      <description>My Hobbies Besides this, writing is also one of my hobbies, ironically having grown more when I no longer had English as a subject in school anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-3/</guid>
      <description>Initium In the Beginning I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by technology since as long as I can remember.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-4/</guid>
      <description>Aut cum scuto aut in scuto One way or the other It was a forbidden place of untold magic to me, the world behind the proverbial curtains, if only sealed off by near impenetrable walls of undecipherable code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-5/</guid>
      <description>Per aspera ad astra Through hardships, to the stars Each time I ventured into these glitches, the few I could manage to find at all that is, I felt like Miles Morales, donning my mask and diving into cyberspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-6/</guid>
      <description>Destitutus ventis, remos adhibe Whatever it takes It was hard, mainly because the developers of that time didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of being able to update their games after it hit shelves, so basically all but the most obscure of bugs were caught when testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-7/</guid>
      <description>Et Ipsa Scientia Potestas Est And knowledge itself, is power I also vividly remember, looking around at all of the electronics surrounding me, things we more often than not take for granted, from the television in the living room to the oven in the kitchen, and the endless sense of bewilderment and wonder that would consume my mind when trying to understand or predict how they worked (and later on when I would take them apart to see for myself).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-8/</guid>
      <description>Sine Qua Non The indispensable reason why And so, driven by a feverish requirement, my hands soon became nimble enough to take apart and reliably be able to put back together quite a lot of things, from remote controlled cars and helicopters to flashlights and blenders and even part of an oven once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/part-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/part-9/</guid>
      <description>Per inānem in scrūtātione īnfīnī Through the void in search of the infinite It has been years, since I wrote that first line of JSON for my Minecraft mod, and years more since I&amp;rsquo;ve loaded up a game on my Gameboy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
